Guide to the Bruce Cratsley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, circa 1970s-1996; Accession 2007-M-042
  - Photographs
    - 10x10 ( and smaller) prints
      - Bucket with Partial Reflections, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Bug Eyes, Gay Parade, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Chris Handling Fruit on Branch, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Dennis Holding Branches of Blossoms, Long Wood Gardens, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Hand and Open Pants ["Hand Opening Jeans, John, Chez Moi, 1987"] (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Hand and Palm, Chez Moi, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Hand of S. Opton, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - John's Hands with Stacked Photos, Chez Moi, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lifting Hand, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Magnolia Forrest (sic), Swarthmore, PA., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Self in Sun, Chez Moi, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Tim Moore, Bicycle Seat, Adam Kurtzman Studio ["Bicycle Seat (Tim Moore), Adam Kurtzman Studio, New York City, 1987"] (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Arthur Tress, Flea Market, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Charlie Descending, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Gay Parade, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Jonathan Looking at Photos, Chez Moi, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Leg of Chris, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Lots of Carrots ["Lots of Carrots, Upper East Side, New York City, 1987"], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - The Empty Chair ["The Empty Chair, Tribeca, New York City, 1984"], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Torn, Lying Figure, in Focus ["Torn (Chris on Polka Dot Sheet, in Sun), 1988"] (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Blocked Manhole, West 17th Street ["Belgian Blocked Manhole, West 17th Street, New York City, 1990"], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Bob Giard, Close-Up, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Coke Classic, Gay Parade, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Flea Market Photos, "Family" ["Triangle of Old Family Photos, Annex Flea Market, New York City, 1987"], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Linda's Make-Up ["Linda Making Up (During Visit with David and Me), 1989"] (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Maine Monument, Gay Day, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ron's Scar, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Skulls ["Two Skulls in Window, New York City, 1986"], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Untitled ["Christopher Sweet Gesturing in Sunlight, Chez Moi, 1989"] (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Big Sugar, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Black-Tiled Bookstore, Different Light, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Bruce and Muffit in Motion at Home, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Elsa Looking at Photos, (Robert Ferro), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Faerie Kiss, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - French Legs, MET Museum, Carpeaux's "Ugolino and His Sons" ["French Legs (Carpeaux's Ugolina and His Sons), Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City, 1989"], 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Gay Teddy, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - He's Got a Big One, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Leopard Haircut, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Lesbians For Patsy Cline, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Madam Photographer, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Margaret, Chez Moi ["Margaret, 1991"], 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Marilyn M., 5th Ave., Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Mr. Faggott, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Parade Protest, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Pumpkin and Crystal Stick ["Pumpkin Bearing Shadow of Crystal Candlestick, At Home, 1994"], 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Self and Woman in Underwear, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Soles, (Jerry D.), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Teddy Bear Chest, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Touched By a Person With Aids, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Triangle and Balloon, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - White Feet, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - White Hat and Gauze, Gay Parade ["Cap and Chiffon, Gay Parade, New York City, 1991"], 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Wigstock Profile, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Untitled ["Artist and Model, Bedroom at Home, 1990"] (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Acting-Up, Gay Parade, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Alphabet Self, Avenue B, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Baby Sascha, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Beverly Hills, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Big Beads and A Kiss, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Death Float, Act Up Float, Gay Parade ["Act Up Float, Gay Parade, New York City, 1992"], 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Doro! (Wigstock), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Dorothy's Shoes ["Dorothy's Shoes, New York City, 1989"], 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Entering and Leaving, Different Light, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Human Washboard, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Loval's Eye, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Moment of Silence, Gay Parade, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Obscured Self, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Plant and Incense by Window, Smoking Face ["Rubber Plant and Smoking Incenses, At Home, 1991"] (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Proust's Chair ["Proust's Chair, Bergdorf Goodman Window, New York City, 1990"], 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Radio Days ["Radio Days, E. Buk Window, Spring Street, New York City, 1991"] (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Self in Magnolia Grove, Swarthmore Campus, Easter, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Three Graces, Wigstock ["The Three Graces, 1990"], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Three More Graces, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Tresses, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - White Hand, Black Jeans, Wigstock, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Untitled ["Fabric Lantern Lit by the Sun, Fire Island Pines, 1991"] (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Big Necklace, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Blond Billy, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Blond Close-up, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Couple, Gay Pride Rally, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Cowrie Necklace, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Dan Martin, P' Town, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Dance Embrace, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Dear God: Please Heal AIDS, Gay Parade ["Dear God: Please Heal AIDS, Gay Parade, New York City, 1992"] (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - El Cid, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Face of Liberty ["Face of Liberty (Colossal), Statue of Liberty Museum, 1992"] (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Feathers and Furs, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Fone-Fella, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Gay Indian Brave, Gay Parade, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Hair Pins, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Heads, Front and Back, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Honey Dog ["Honey Dog, At Home, 1992"] (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - John and Rob, Gay Pride Rally, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - John's Shorts, Close-up, Gay Pride Rally, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Masked Robert, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Medusa, Verso, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Michael's Hand, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Moon Man, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Moon-Man with Flowers, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - On the Fence, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Pretty Girl, Gay Parade, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Pride Guy, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Robert's Shoe, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Self at Bus Stop, 80th and Madison, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Stars in Her Hair, (Big Smile), Wigstock ["Stars in Her Hair, Wigstock, 1992"] (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Tit Pinch, Gay Parade, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Toy Boxes, E. Buk Window, Spring St. ["Three Toy Boxes, E. Buk Window, Spring Street, Soho, New York City, 1992"] (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Transvestite Close-up, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Two Youths, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - When Your [sic] Having Only One, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Wig and a Smile, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Wigstock Mohawk, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Young Beauty, Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Young Man (Innocence), Wigstock, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Young Man with Whistle, Gay Parade, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Untitled ["Billy and Bruce at Barney's, 1992"] (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Self at Dancing Bear's [Home of William Hunt], 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Action = Life, (Brad Lam), Gay Pride Rally, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Arm and Waist, Gay Pride Rally ["Man Holding Man, Gay Pride Rally, 1992"], 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Artist and Model, (Bedroom), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Bald Head In Shaving Mirror, Self at Franklin Furnace, Tribeca, NYC, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Beth Israel (White Hand), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Billy with a Magazine ["Billy with a Magazine, in Winter Light, 1993"] (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Birthday Branches of Orchids, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Black and White Couple, Gay Pride Rally, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Branches in Bloom, Windy Willows, variant of, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Close-up Self, Beth Israel, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Easter Window, Billy & Bruce, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Foot and Plant, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Foot in Bed, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Hairy Chest and Head, Wigstock, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Heel of Foot, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Hospital Self, (Post-Craniotomy), 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Hyacinth Vases, Close-Up, Windywillows ["Vases in Window, Windywillows, Truro, 1993"] (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Man with Boa, Wigstock, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Portrait of Ned Bayrd, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Self Photographing at Home ["Photographer and Model Reflected in Mirror, Chez Moi, 1994"], 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Stamens and Pistols, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Stamens and Pistols, (Billy Watching TV), 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Straw Hat, Gay Pride Rally, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Taped Wall and Bucket of Trash ["Trashed Paint Can, Chelsea, New York City, 1986"], 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Tattoed Ankle, Gay Parade, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - White Hand and Arm, Wigstock, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Untitled ["Self with Downcast Eyes, At Home, 1993"] (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Bedroom, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Billy and Self, Bedroom, Chez Moi, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Billy Asleep, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Black Dancer, Gay Parade, 1994(?) (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Coptic Mummy Case, MET Museum ["Coptic Mummy Case, Metropolitan Musum of Art, New York City, 1994"] (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Dali Sculpture, MOMA, NYC ["Salvador Dali's Retrospective Bust of Woman, Museum of Modern Art, New York City, 1994"] (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Golden Mask, MET Museum ["Reliquary Mask, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City, 1995"], 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Hand of Warren, Chez Moi, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Is This Really Happening? Gay Parade, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Pile of Books on Victorian Chair, Chez Moi ["Pile of Books on Needlepoint Chair, At Home, 1994"] (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Porch at Wilderstein (Plants and Posts) ["Porch at Wilderstein, Hudson River Valley, 1994"] (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Porch with Plant and Chair, Hudson Valley ["White Chair an Plant, Wilderstein, Hudson River Valley, 1994"] (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Self Reflected in Antique Mirror, Cohen Barn, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Self Reflected in Barn Door, Copake, N.Y., Cohen's Barn, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Shadow of Perseus ["Shadow of Canova's Perseus, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York City, 1990"], 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Style S, (Billy L.), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Warren Muller (Hand on Face), Chez Moi ["Warren with His Hand to His Face, Chez Moi"], 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Wooden Rocker, Copake, N.Y. ["Rustic Chair near the Cohen's Barn, Copake, New York, 1994"] (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Bill Cullum, HIV Positive Tatoo [sic], Day without Art, MET Museum Steps, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Están aquí tres privilegios de iuro y renta dados por el excelentísimo señor marqués de Montesclaros, virrey, governador y capitán general del Perú...sobre su real hacienda y rentas destos reinos en favor de Antonio Correa...., 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Carved Statue of a Saint, Louvre, Paris ["Medieval Figure of Bearded Man, Louvre, Paris, 1985"], 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Ivory Reliquary Hand of Benediction, Paris, Louvre, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Le Vase in Shop Window, Paris, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Melancholic Saint, (Wooden?), Paris ["Melancholic Saint, Medieval Collection, Louvre, Paris, 1995"] (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Mourning Paul (sic) Bearer, Sarcophagus of Philppe Pot, Seneschal of Burgundy, 15th C: French, Louvre, Paris ["Hooded Mourner, Tomb of Philippe Pot, Seneschel of Burgundy, 15th Century French, Louvre, Paris, 1995"] (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Painted, Old Brass Lantern, E. Buk Shop Window, Spring Street, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Paris Street in Early November Afternoon Light, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Self In Florist Shop Window, Paris ["Self Reflected in Florist Shop Window, Paris, 1995"] (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Self Reflected in Ornate 2nd Empire Mirror, Paris, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Wood Mannequin Wearing Silk, Cravat and Vest, Paris ["Hand of Antique Wooden Mannequin, Paris Window, 1995"] (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Untitled ["Darkroom Levitation, 1996"] (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Untitled [variant of "Corner of My Darkroom with Irene Fay's Portrait of Lisette Model, 1996"] (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Untitled ["Delphiniums, At Home, 1997"] (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Untitled (Gay Parade), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Untitled (Gay Parade), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Untitled (Hand), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Untitled (Self-portrait), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Untitled (Self-portrait), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Untitled (Self-portrait), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Untitled (Self-portrait), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Untitled (Self-portrait), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Untitled (Shadows), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Untitled (Shop window), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Topical files
    - Biographical, circa 1987-1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980-1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Galleries, circa 1985-1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photography, general, circa 1988-1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Projects
      - Shows, 1980-1996 (Box 10, Folder 5-9)
        - Oversize mounted reviews (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Shows, 1997-1998 and undated (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
        - Oversize mounted reviews (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Other projects
        - General, 1981-1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
        - White Light, Silent Shadows, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 4)
          - Oversize, circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 11, Folder 5)